本字幕由大家字幕組原創翻譯制作僅供學習 禁止用于任何商業盈利行為若因私自散布傳播造成法律問題 本字幕組概不負責更多影視請搜索并關注新浪微博  大家字幕組
翻譯： 天然緋  lilbear  Cindy  筱欣
校對：連續三天翻譯加校對要瘋的肉肉
時間軸&特效：愛狼崽崽不忍完結的靖宇么么噠艾瑞寶滴23333
時間軸&特效：600米要跑一個月終于跑了第一天的Sandra
壓制： 暴牙弟
公元1536年 亨利八世對安妮·博林由愛轉恨再到不信任
他現在的注意力都移到了簡·西摩的身上
亨利暗授克倫威爾助他擺脫他那位第二任王后
隨著安妮的失寵
她的敵人們逐漸聚集
真該死 我們什么時候能開餐 克倫威爾
Damn! When are we going to eat, Cromwell?
我要餓暈了
I'm famished!
狼·廳
第1季 第6集
你最喜歡哪個呢
Which is your favourite?
小泳帽嗎
Swim hat?
特別漂亮是不是
Very pretty, isn't it?
這是刺繡工匠剛呈上的
It's just come from the embroiderer.
是不是很可愛
Isn't it sweet?
戴在她的小腦袋上
For her little head.
克倫威爾
Cremuel?
我聽說 當你以為國王駕崩時
I am told that when you thought the King was dead,
你的第一反應竟然是傳召那個私生女瑪麗
your first action was to send for the bastard Mary.
你竟然沒有考慮過我
You did not think of me,
和我的女兒
or my daughter
和我當時身上懷著的寶寶
or the child I was carrying then.
我不能把王位交給一個尚在襁褓中的嬰兒
I cannot hold the throne for an infant in the cradle.
更不能交給一個尚未出世的孩子
I cannot hold the throne for an unborn baby.
是我提拔的你
I promoted you.
我是你地位提升如此之快的因素
I am responsible for your rise.
可一旦出現了機會 你卻背叛了我
And at the first opportunity, you have betrayed me.
夫人 我做的事都不是出于私心的
Madam, nothing here is personal.
你覺得你已羽翼豐滿
You think you've grown great.
不再需要我的庇護
You think you no longer need me,
但你卻忘記了最為重要的一件事
but you've forgotten the most important thing.
克倫威爾
Cremuel!
所有的事情都可以推倒重來
Those who've been made can be unmade.
我不能同意更多
I entirely agree.
我們想驅逐那個姘婦
We want the concubine ousted.
我們知道你也很想這樣
We know you want it too.
"我們" 指的是
We?
我有些很覬覦 也與王位有血緣關系的朋友們
My friends in this matter are very near the throne,
愛德華國王一脈的家族
those in the line of old King Edward.
比如埃克塞特大人 考特尼家族
Lord Exeter, the Courtenay family.
蒙塔古大人 他的哥哥 杰弗里·波利  瑪格麗特·波利夫人
Lord Montague, his brother, Geoffrey Pole, Lady Margaret Pole.
這些都是我交談過的最有分量的人了
These are the principal persons on whose behalf I speak.
我還給你提個醒
But, as you will be aware,
大部分英國民眾都會很高興國王罷黜她
the most part of England would rejoice to see the King free of her.
我可不認為大部分英國子民會知道或在意這事
I don't think the most part of England knows or cares.
那你們到底需要我做什么
What do you require of me?
我們...需要...你加入我們
We...require...that you join us.
我們想要把西摩家的女兒推上王后之位
We're content to have Seymour's girl crowned.
她因熱愛真實的宗教信仰而聞名
She's known to favour true religion
而我們也相信她能讓亨利與羅馬教廷重歸于好
and we believe she will bring Henry back to Rome.
但這也正是我們的難處 克倫威爾
And this is our difficulty, Cromwell.
我們知道 你是個路德會教友
We know you are a Lutheran.
什么 我不是 先生 我只是個銀行主
Me? No, sir. I'm a banker.
那你們會怎么處理安妮·博林
What will happen to Anne Boleyn?
我不知道
I don't know.
可能遣送到康文特去吧
Convent?
看這個小可憐哦
Look at this little doggie.
噢 你為什么看上去這么悲傷 馬克
Oh, why are you so sad, Mark?
你根本勿須憂傷
You have no business being sad.
你在這里是為了愉悅我們的
You're here to entertain us.
噢 我的天 你給我站好了
Oh, for heaven's sake, stand on your feet.
我給你面子才看你一眼
I do you favour by noticing you at all.
你還指望什么
What do you expect?
你覺得我應該像和紳士一般說話的和你說話嗎
Do you think I should talk to you as if you were a gentleman?
但我做不到 馬克 你看
But I can't do that, Mark. You see...
因為你本身就是個下等人
because you're an inferior person.
是的 王后
No, madam.
我什么都沒有指望的
I don't expect a word.
您看我一眼 已能使我滿足
A look suffices me.
是嗎
Well?
那你現在是不是要開始贊頌我的眼睛了
Aren't you going to praise my eyes now?
你為什么要鼓勵那個男孩
Why do you encourage that boy?
所有有禮貌的寵物都該得到鼓勵的
All manner of puppy dogs are encouraged here.
有些時候進來的不合時宜
Some are coming in AND out of season.
你是在引用我的話嗎 諾里斯
Are you referring to me, Norris?
要是能一腳踢一下那"寵物"的肚腩 真是要樂死了
I could happily give this puppy dog a kick in his ribs
- 他就永遠不會忘了  - 不許在我的宮殿內隨便踢 拜托
- that he won't forget.  - No kicking in my chamber, if you please.
他把自己弄得這么焦慮
He gets himself agitated
因為他總覺得我到這里來是想勾搭瑪麗夫人的
because he thinks I come here to cast my fancy at Lady Mary.
我們都知道其實是他自己想娶瑪麗夫人
We all know he hopes to marry her himself.
但說真的 我到這來 是為了另一個女人的
But really I come here for the sake of another.
- 你知道我是為誰來嗎  - 不知道 你告訴我吧
- And do you know who that is?  - No, tell me.
我猜不到
I can't guess.
難道是羅奇福德夫人嗎
Is it Lady Rochford here?
肯定不會是年齡這么大的吧
Surely not one so old?
是您 王后
No. It is yourself, Madam.
諾里斯 或許你該踹他一腳
Perhaps you should kick him, Gentle Norris,
以維護英格蘭王后的尊嚴
for the honour of the Queen of England.
來了個我的親信
Ah! Here's the man for me.
這位威爾·布里爾頓能把弓箭筆直的射出去
Will Brereton is one who shoots his arrow straight.
你們在干嘛呢
What's to do here?
每個人都在爭吵 起源于那個叫馬克的男孩
Everyone's been fighting, and all because of that boy Mark.
我覺得他應該從高空扔下去
I think he should be dropped from a great height.
就像你的那條小狗 博克爾
Just like your dog, Purkoy.
你再扇一次 我就會還手了
Do that again and I will hit you back.
你不是王后 你不過是個騎士的女兒
You're no queen. You're just a knight's daughter
而且你大限將至了
and your time has come.
哈里
Harry?
幫我個忙 把我的這位弟妹帶走 然后將她溺死
Do me a good turn - take away my brother's wife and drown her.
- 安妮  - 干嘛
- Anne!  - What?
你不是曾發誓說 愿意為我赤腳走路到中國去的嗎
Didn't you swear you'd walk barefoot to China for me?
我記得我說的是赤腳走到沃爾辛厄姆
I think it was barefoot to Walsingham I offered.
那或許你能在那邊懺悔你的罪孽
Perhaps you can repent your sins there.
因為如何國王有任何不測 你會想盡辦法得到我的
Because if anything happened to the King, you'd look to have me.
噢 不好意思了 瑪麗 你知道他為什么一直不娶你嗎
Oh, yes, you see now, Mary, why he hasn't married you yet?
因為他一直愛的都是我 據他所說是這樣的
It's because he's in love with me. Or so he claims.
而現在 他也不愿把羅奇福德夫人裝進袋子里 扔到河里面
And yet he won't prove it by putting Lady Rochford in a sack
來證明對我的愛了
and dropping her in the river.
那你愿意分享你的全部秘密嗎 安妮 還是只有一部分
Will you spill all your secrets, Anne, or only some?
把他...把他叫回來
Oh, he... Get him back.
我剛剛是氣話 快把他叫回來
It was idle talk. Get him back.
讓他回來 他會對著圣經起誓
Get him back and he'll swear on the Bible.
他知道我會是一個好妻子的
He knows me to be a good wife.
快讓他回來 哈里
Get him back! Harry!
亨利聽說了她和諾里斯之間的爭吵
Henry had heard about the fight with Norris.
我們從庭院里都看到了
We could all see from the courtyard.
她把她的手...
She had her hands...
你知道國王最愛的織錦的
You know the King's great tapestry?
王后將它一起握在手上
Where the Queen clasps her hands together?
但國王顯然沒有被說服
He didn't look persuaded.
你沒有去勸慰一下她嗎
Did you not go to her to comfort her?
她畢竟是你的女主人
She being your mistress?
沒有 我直接來找你商討了
No. I came looking for you.
在他們結婚之前
Before they were married,
安妮曾與亨利練習過
Anne used to practise with Henry.
做一些新奇的玩法
In the French fashion.
你知道我什么意思的
You know what I mean.
羅奇福德夫人 我不知道你的意思
Lady Rochford, I have no idea what you mean.
噢 你以為我會羞恥的不好意思說出我的意思來嗎
Oh, you think you can shame me out of saying what I must say?
我可不是一個處女
I'm no virgin girl.
她勾引他把他的精子 射到了個不正常的地方
She induced him to put his seed otherwise than he should have.
現在亨利稱之為一個骯臟的口
Now Henry calls it a filthy proceeding.
但上帝還是愛他 他不知道那里一開始裝的什么
But God love him, he doesn't know where the filth begins.
我的丈夫喬治...
My husband George...
..總是和安妮混在一起
..is always with Anne.
他是她弟弟 這很正常
He's her brother. It's natural.
但喬治沒有正常的一面
There's nothing natural in George.
在他眼里 沒有什么是不可以做的
And nothing is forbidden.
我曾見過他們接吻
I've seen them kiss.
弟弟親吻姐姐沒什么...
Brothers may kiss their sis...
他的舌頭在她的嘴里 她的舌頭也在他嘴里
His tongue in her mouth. Hers in his.
你想讓我將這件事記錄在案嗎
You want me to record that?
如果你害怕 這件事你不會記住的
If you're worried you won't remember it.
可她為什么要做出這樣的事
Why would she do such a thing?
你知道為什么的 為了更好地統治
You know why. The better to rule.
假如她生下了一個男孩 卻而且有著威斯頓的長臉
Suppose she gets a boy and it has Weston's long face?
或者看著像威爾·布里爾頓
Or looks like Will Brereton?
但如果長得像博林家的孩子 就沒理由說他是私生子了
But they can't call it a bastard if it looks like a Boleyn.
我衷心建議你
Be advised by me.
千萬別告訴任何人
Speak to no-one.
我也衷心建議你
Be advised by me.
去和馬克·斯米頓談談吧
Speak to Mark Smeaton.
我們可以把那個留在這 馬克
We can leave that here, Mark.
我還以為會有一幫人呢
I thought there was to be a great company?
我以為我是負責來愉悅你的
I thought I was going to entertain you.
毫無疑問
Make no doubt of it.
你看 馬克
You see, Mark,
我的主人 國王 和我的女主人 王后
my master, the King, and my mistress, the Queen,
發生了分歧
are at odds.
每個人都知道
Everyone knows.
而我最大的心愿就是他們能夠和好
And my dearest wish is to reconcile them.
可你在議會上說的話 就好像是你在與王后的敵人為伍
The word at court is you're keeping company with the Queen's enemies.
那不然我怎能察覺出他們的動機圖謀
How else am I to find out their practices?
信你才怪
Ah. If only I could believe that.
我不怪你 馬克
I don't blame you, Mark.
在議會上這種惡心的地方 人與人無信任可言
There's such ill-feeling at the court, no-one trusts anyone.
但是我找你來 是因為你和王后的關系密切
But I've come to you because you're close to the Queen,
我也真的很想知道 她為什么如此不高興
and I'd really love to know why she's so unhappy
有什么事我能做的
and if there's anything that I can do to remedy it.
難怪她不開心
It's no wonder she's unhappy.
她正在熱戀中
She's in love.
和誰
With whom?
和我
With me.
你看起來很吃驚
You're amazed.
我...
I'm...
我沒有你想象的那么吃驚
I'm not as amazed as you might think.
我知道她是怎么看你的
I've seen how she looks at you.
這不奇怪 任何女人都會被你吸引的
And it's no surprise that any woman would be drawn to you.
你是一個非常英俊的年輕小伙
You're a very handsome young man.
但是我們覺得你是個孌童
But we thought you were a sodomite.
里奇
Rich!
我是和他們一樣的男人
I'm as good a man as any of them.
當然 相信王后也會給你一個很好的地位
Of course you are and the Queen would give you good report.
她審視過你 發現你很對她的胃口
She's tried you. Found you to her liking.
我不想討論這個
I can't discuss it.
不 不 你可以不討論 但我們可以假設
No, no, you mustn't. But we can assume.
她不是一個沒有經驗的女人
She's not an inexperienced woman.
我想她不會對一個經驗少 表現拙劣的人感興趣的
I think she would not be interested in anything less than a masterly performance.
好吧 我會說
Well, I will say this -
我們出身貧寒的人
we men born poor
還做出那樣卑賤的行為是不明智的
are in no wise inferior in that way.
很正確
How true.
盡管貴族的紳士們 喜歡對女士們的保留秘密
Though the noble gentlemen like to keep that secret from the ladies.
他們不想要競爭 對吧
They wouldn't want the competition, would they?
如果你的意思是她是否有別的情人 這我不知道
If you mean she has other lovers, I wouldn't know.
我沒有問過她
I haven't asked her.
- 但是他們都嫉妒我   - 是嗎?
- But they're jealous of me. - Are they?
- 威斯頓和諾里斯 這些大人們
- Weston and Norris, those lords.
他們叫我小男孩 但我知道他們是嫉妒我
They call me boy, but they're jealous.
好吧 也許她也試探了他們 而他們卻令人失望了
Well, perhaps she tried them and they were a disappointment.
你則是贏家
And you take the prize.
多久一次
How often?
你已經給我們兩個名字了 馬克
You've given us two names, Mark.
現在說出其他人的名字吧
Now name the others.
然后回答理查德學士 多久一次
And answer Master Richard. How often?
嗯 也許你不說話是明智的
Perhaps you're wise not to speak.
最好把名單都寫下來
Best to have it all written down.
否則議會很難相信它的真實性
The council will hardly believe it otherwise.
他們會為你的成功感到驚訝 甚至嫉妒
They'll be amazed at your success. Jealous.
他們會問 "斯米頓 你的秘密是什么"
"Smeaton, what is your secret?" they'll demand.
你會回答 "啊 我不能透露"
And you'll answer, "Ah, I can't impart."
但是你終要說的 馬克
But you will impart, Mark.
你會自愿說出來
You'll do it freely.
或者被迫說
Or you'll do it enforced.
坐下吧 俊俏的小男孩
Seat yourself, pretty boy.
我收回我的話 我不會告訴你任何名字的
I take it back. I can't give you any names.
我不知道我怎么會到這來 說我做了什么
I don't know how I came to say what I did.
不 我也是 沒有人傷害你或強迫你的 你可以暢所欲言
No, nor do I. No-one hurt you or coerced you. You spoke freely.
這兩位先生是我的證人
These two gentlemen are my witnesses.
我收回我說的話
I take it back.
我可不這么認為
I don't think so.
告訴我們 你和王后通奸
Tell us about your adultery with the Queen
還有你所知道的她和其他男人的來往
and what you know about her dealings with the other gentlemen
如果你的供述是真實完整的
and IF your confession is true and full,
說不定國王會憐憫你 饒你一命
perhaps the King will show you mercy.
你愿意和理查德學士在這 獨處十分鐘嗎
Would you like to spend ten minutes alone with Master Richard here?
五分鐘就行了
Five would do it.
他會如實寫下你所說的 馬克
He will write down what you say, Mark.
但他不一定會寫下我們所對你做的
But he won't necessarily write down what we do.
噢 天啊
Oh, God!
你聽懂了嗎
Do you follow me?
圣母瑪利亞 救救我
Mother Mary, help me.
我不能告訴你們 我并不知道的事啊
I can't tell you what I don't know.
你不能嗎
Can't you?
不能
No.
好吧 那看來你是我們今晚留宿的客人了 馬克
Well, then you'll have to be my guest for the night, Mark.
噢 求求你了
Oh! Please.
好吧 他們中沒有多少人還活著了
Well, there aren't many men alive
他們還真是嚇了我一跳
who can say they took me by surprise.
常年被貴族們渲染 已經讓他變得大言不慚
Years of being despised by lords has made a boaster of him.
有時候我覺得我應該帶他來這里
Sometimes I think I should have taken him in here.
我不想傷害他
I don't want him hurt.
如果我們必須要像折磨可憐的生物那樣 接下來怎么做
If we have to torture sad creatures like that, what next?
踩踏睡鼠
Stamping on dormice?
讓里奧謝思利明天過來
Tell Wriothesley to come tomorrow.
這是什么
What is this?
這是幽靈住的地方
It's where the phantom lives.
進去吧
In you go.
拜托
Please!
讓我出去 請讓我出去吧
Let me out! Please let me out!
讓我出去啊
Let me out!
有哈里·諾里斯和佛朗西斯·威斯頓
Henry Norris, Francis Weston.
以及威廉·布里爾頓和佛朗西斯·布萊恩
And William Brereton and Francis Bryan.
理查德·朗 沃爾特·沃爾什
Richard Long, Walter Walsh.
你和王后 到底有過多少次茍且之事
You had to do with the Queen - how many times?
得有上千次了 三四次而已
A thousand? Three or four.
三四次而已
Three or four.
理查德
Richard.
去格林威治覲見國王
Go to the King at Greenwich.
他在等著見你
He'll be expecting you.
千萬不要相信任何一個人
Trust your message to no-one.
要親自把消息送入他耳里
Put the word in his ear yourself
佩奇
Page!
讓哈里·諾里斯從叢林里回來
Tell Henry Norris to retire from the field.
哈里 和我一起騎段路
Ride with me, Harry.
去哪里 陛下
Where to, my lord?
就我們倆 隨便聊聊
Let's talk, you and I.
克倫威爾
Cromwell!
我聽說玩音樂的小子最后都幾乎按照你的調子在唱歌了
I hear the singer sang to your tune.
你對他做了什么啊
What did you do to him?
我有個歌謠要說給你聽
There's a pretty ballad for you.
國王在彈琴的時候 他的琴師卻在"彈"著王后
The King fingers his lute, while his lutenist fingers his wife.
你帶搜查令了嗎 大人
You have the warrant, my lord?
或許這樣能教育亨利多聽聽我的
Perhaps this'll teach Henry to listen to me.
叔父
Uncle.
大法官閣下
Lord Chancellor.
財政大臣閣下
Master Treasurer.
還有克倫威爾
And Cremuel.
我親手栽培出來的男人
The man I created.
不 夫人 是他親手扶植你上位的
He created you in turn, madam.
我確信他自己也在懊悔的
And be sure he repents of it.
但是我先感到遺憾的
Oh, but I was sorry first.
也遺憾的更多
And I am sorry more.
準備好出發了嗎
Ready to go?
我不知該如何準備
I don't know how to be ready.
只要跟我們走就好
Just come with us.
都怪我
I'm to blame.
我懷疑了她 卻無計可施
I suspected her and did nothing.
我...
I...
我從未對一個女人 有像對她那樣的好印象
I never had a better opinion in a woman than I had in her.
我至今仍不敢相信她有罪
I can't believe she's guilty.
只是我知道如果她無罪的話 國王陛下是不會這么做的
Except I know Your Highness would never go so far if she weren't.
她欺騙了我們所有人
She deceived all of us.
我現在回想起來 也都想明白了
When I look back, it all falls into place.
失去了那么多的朋友
So many friends lost,
漸行漸遠...
alienated...
很是糟心
Worse.
每當我想起沃爾西的時候...
When I think of Wolsey...
想起了安妮與他作對的樣子
The way she practised against him.
她說她是愛我的
She said she loved me.
但是其實她一點也不愛我
But she meant the opposite.
我寫過一個劇本
I've written a play.
是一個悲劇
A tragedy.
我自己的故事
My own story.
您先留著吧 陛下 等我們有足夠的閑暇時間來品鑒它
You should keep it sir, till we have more leisure to do it justice.
但我想要讓你們看看她的本性
But I want you to see her true nature.
我相信她已經與上百個男人通奸過了
I believe she has committed adultery with 100 men.
但和她的弟弟
But her brother?
真的有可能嗎
Is it likely?
我還不相信她能抵擋誘惑
Well, I doubt she could resist!
為何要寬恕呢
Why spare?
明知是破鞋 為何還要穿
Why not drink the cup to its filthy dregs?
來吧 沃爾西 我們領你到地獄來
Come, Wolsey, we're fetching you to Hell,
我們的主人 別西卜圣經中的鬼王] 正等著你共進晚餐呢
where our master, Beelzebub, is expecting you to supper!
別西卜愿意與你共享鹿肉
Beelzebub would have you joint his venison.
他聽說你擅長屠殺
He's heard of your skill as a butcher!
我知道為什么我在這里
I know why I'm here.
因為我的妻子
My wife.
她說了什么
What has she said?
不管說了什么 你都不能因為一個女人的一面之詞而抓我
Whatever it is, you can't hold me on the word of one woman.
也有其他女人說起了
There've been other women who have been recipients
你的風流往事 喬治
of your...gallantry, George.
你一直就覺得女人是可以玩玩就扔的...
You've always regarded women as disposable...
怎么
What?
你要因為我的風流韻事而審訊我嗎
You're going to put me on trial for gallantry?
不曾想與一個自愿和我共赴巫山的情人在一起 居然是犯罪
I didn't know it was a crime to spend time with a willing lover.
如果那個女人是你的親姐姐時 那就是犯罪了
It is when that lover is your sister.
我的家族世世代代為英國國王效勞
My family has served the King of England for generations.
我自小就在亨利的左右服侍了
I have been at the side of Henry since I was a boy.
我愛他就像愛自己的兄弟一樣 我從未忘記過我的榮幸...
I love him like a brother. I would never forget my honour, never...
還需要我把事情挑明了嗎 諾里斯
Do you want me to write it on the wall for you, Norris?
她不能給他生下個子嗣
She can't give him a son.
他要再娶一個妻子
He wants another wife.
她不會就這樣保持沉默的
She won't go quietly.
這樣對你來說夠簡單明了吧
Is that simple enough for your simple tastes?
她需要別人給她施壓 我必須要給她壓力
She has to be PUSHED. I have to PUSH her.
好吧 反正我是不會認罪的
Well, you'll get no confession from me,
布里爾頓也不會的
or Brereton either.
你不會對一位紳士用刑的
You'll not torture gentlemen.
國王是不會同意的
The King wouldn't permit it.
那我們可以私底下來做點安排
There don't have to be formal arrangements.
我能把我的大拇指插進你的眼中
I can put my thumbs in your eyes
然后你會唱 "冬青樹郁郁又蔥蔥"...
and then you would sing Green Grows The Holly...
我叫你做什么 你就做什么
if I asked you to.
懂了嗎
Hmm?
我們再重新談過
Let's go back.
我記得在紅衣主教大人末年
I remember in the late Cardinal's time,
你的一個家人在弓箭比賽上殺了一個人
one of your household killed a man in a bowls match.
你知道刀劍不長眼
Well, the game can get very heated.
紅衣主教覺得是時候算算賬了
The Cardinal thought it was time for a reckoning,
但是你的家人在調查過程中故意阻撓
but your family impeded the investigation
我就問自己 "打那之后有什么變化嗎"
and I ask myself, "Has anything changed since then?"
約翰艾頓在最近和你的一個王室成員有過爭執
John ap Eyton had a quarrel with one of your household only recently.
所以 這就是我在此的原因吧
So, that's why I'm here.
不全是 但暫且不提你和王后通奸的事
Not entirely, but leave aside your adultery with the Queen,
我們先專注于伊頓
let's concentrate on Eyton.
他在與人互相射箭中 誤殺了對方
Blows were exchanged, a man was killed.
伊頓經過審訊被無罪釋放了
Eyton was tried and acquitted.
但是你 因為你對法律的不敬...
But you, because you have no respect for the law or...
- 我充分的尊重法律   - 不許打斷我
- I have every respect! - Don't interrupt me!
你綁架了那個人并絞死了他
You had the man abducted and hanged.
你以為僅僅只是一個人 無關緊要是嗎
You think because it's only one man, it doesn't matter.
你以為沒有人會記得住 可我記得
You think no-one will remember, but I remember.
你以為有諾爾福克罩著你 你就能為所欲為了嗎
You think you can do anything because Norfolk favours you...
是國王罩著我的
The King favours me!
是嗎 他是罩著你的嗎
Does he? Does he?
那你或許能和國王去抱怨一下你的居住環境 對吧
Well, you should complain about your lodgings, then, shouldn't you?
不過后來 佛朗西斯·布萊恩向我解釋了
But then, Francis Bryan has been explaining it to me...
布萊恩
Bryan?
- 布萊恩可是我的敵人  - 我也意識到了
- Bryan is an enemy of mine. - And I begin to see it.
你怎么會對你姐姐有所了解呢
How a man may hardly know his sister.
畢竟她在法國長大
She grows up in France.
成年后才相見 但她很像他
They meet as adults, she is like him, yet not.
她很熟知他
She is familiar,
然后 她激起了他的興趣
and yet, she piques his interest.
直到有一天 弟弟的擁抱 比尋常持續的時間更久
One day, his brotherly embrace lasts a little longer than usual.
從那時起 不正當關系便發生了
The business proceeds from there.
或許你們倆從沒覺得自己做錯任何事
Perhaps neither of you felt you were doing anything wrong.
直到突破了底線
Until some frontier was crossed.
我拒絕回答這個問題
I refuse to answer this.
你們的關系是開始在她與國王的婚禮之前 還是之后
Did it begin before her marriage to the King, or afterwards?
喬治兄弟 你一定很驚詫
Brother George, that must have been a surprise.
對立由此而生
Rivalry from that quarter.
但是你的紳士品格還是讓我驚異
But the morality of you gentlemen astonishes me.
我對喬治沒有任何意見
I have no opinion of George.
對近親通奸也沒有意見嗎
No opinion of incest?
你說得如此平淡 我想這一定是真的了
You take it so quietly I'm forced to think it must be true...
如果我說是 你就會指責我
If I said it was, you'd only accuse me of trying
在轉移你對我的注意力
to divert attention away from myself.
哈里 你真是太了解我了
You've known me too long, Harry.
我曾研究過你
Oh, I've studied you.
也還研究過沃爾西
Studied Wolsey before you.
你曾多么的謹慎 一個國家的忠實仆從
That was politic of you. Such a great servant of the state!
到最后又成了個偉大的叛徒
And such a great traitor at the end.
我還記著在法庭上很有趣的一幕 你還記得嗎
I remember a certain entertainment at court, do you remember?
一場表演秀 紅衣主教被惡魔們打倒
A play, in which the late Cardinal was set upon by demons
被扯到地獄里去了
and dragged down to hell.
你就是因為這個記恨我嗎
That's why?
它是
It...
那只是一個表演秀而已
It was a play!
只是一個玩笑 你不能...
It was a joke! You can't...
- 你不能當真...  - 你要用一生來償還
- You can't seriously... - Life pays you out.
你沒這覺悟嗎
Don't you find?
那馬克·斯米頓呢
But Mark Smeaton?
- 他對你做了什么  - 不知道
- What has he done to you? - I don't know...
我就是不喜歡他看我的眼神
I just don't like the way he looks at me.
哈里 我需要有罪的人
I need guilty men, Harry.
所以我就盡可能的去尋找有罪之人
So, I've found men who ARE guilty.
雖然他們的罪 還不至于被判刑
Though not necessarily as charged.
早上好
Good morning.
我剛剛結婚
I'm not long married.
你可能不知道 我還有個兒子
I don't know if you know that. I have a son...
你有債務在身 高達一千英鎊
You have debts. To the tune of a thousand pounds.
那個魔頭為什么要提到這件事
Why the devil bring that up...?
沒有人奢求像你一樣揮霍無度的年輕人 能夠勤儉持家
No-one expects a young gallant like yourself to be thrifty,
可是你的債務 遠超出你的償還能力了
but these debts are more than you could reasonably pay.
所以你的放縱揮霍的行為 讓人們不由得去想
So, your own extravagance gives people to think,
這個年輕的威斯頓到底存著怎樣的心思
what expectations did young Weston have?
我們都清楚王后給了你不少錢
We know the Queen gave you money.
如果你能娶了她 一千英磅對你來說根本就不算什么了
A thousand pounds is nothing to you if you hoped to marry her
所以你謀劃了國王的謀殺
after you'd contrived the King's death.
當證據呈出時 我才知道了事情的嚴重性
I see how it'll weigh, when it's given in evidence.
我悔過自新了
I've undone myself.
克倫威爾 我不怪你
I don't blame you, Cromwell.
只是...
It's just...
...我以為還能再活二十年的
..I thought I had another 20 years.
佛朗西斯 我們都知道 你活不過二十小時了
Well, we know not the hour, do we, Francis?
你搞定了嗎
Are you finished?
他有告發其他人嗎
Has he denounced the others?
你想讓我們來逼他說嗎
Do you want us to make him?
怎么 你認為我對年輕人太溫柔了嗎
What? What, do you think I'm too soft on young men?!
- 那你想讓我們起草起訴書嗎? - 嗯 罪狀越多越好
- Do you want us to draw up charges? - Yeah, the more the merrier.
請見諒 我要去方便一下
Forgive me, I have to piss.
叛徒
Traitor!
我夫人在陪著她
My wife is with her.
還有她的姨母 謝爾頓夫人
And her aunt, Lady Shelton.
她怎么樣了
How is she?
一會兒哭 一會兒笑
Sometimes crying, sometimes laughing.
還在自言自語什么
There's something she said.
我提起這個 只是因為你下令 要報告我所聽到的一切事情而已
I only mention it because you told me to report everything I heard.
繼續
Go on.
當我告訴她 她要住在
When I told her she would stay in the same room
加冕之前 居住的房子里
she had before her coronation,
她說 "你們對我太好了
she said, "It's too good for me.
耶穌也是在憐憫我"
Jesus have mercy on me."
如果她不值得這一切 因為她有戴罪之人
If she's not worthy, it's because she's guilty.
但是她到底做了什么
But what is it she's done?
是我們根本難以想象的嗎
Is it something we haven't even imagined yet?'
你喜歡那件帶來的毛皮衣服嗎
Would you like your furs brought in?
是貂皮的
The ermine.
還有我不想看到這群女人 我想要回我的侍女們
And I don't want these women. I want my own women.
金斯頓夫人是
Lady Kingston is...
你的間諜
Your spy.
...是女主人
..your hostess.
那我就是個客人了嗎
Am I a guest, then?
那我能離開嗎
Am I free to go?
你不該違抗你的姨母的
I didn't think you'd object to your own aunt.
她對我滿懷怨恨 滿耳朵都是她的抱怨聲
She has a grudge against me. All I hear is tutting.
那你難道還期望有掌聲嗎
Do you expect applause?
等我被釋放了 你就不敢沖我這樣說話了
You won't speak to me that way to me after I'm released.
我不清楚國王為什么要把我軟禁在這
I don't know why the King is holding me here.
我想這應該是某種考驗吧
I suppose it's some sort of test, isn't it?
我想見我的弟弟
I want to see my brother.
在這種情況之下 真是一個愚蠢的要求
That's a foolish demand in the circumstances.
- 那要見我父親 - 不要期望有人會幫你
- My father. - Don't expect help there.
托馬斯·博林會一直照看著他
Thomas Boleyn looks after himself first and last.
我知道 因為他是我的哥哥
I should know, he's my brother.
別為難國王了
Help the King.
除非他仁慈至極 否則你根本無能為力
Unless he's merciful, there's nothing you can do for yourself.
不過你應當為你的女兒做些事
But you can do something for your daughter.
為伊麗莎白做點事
For Elizabeth.
在整個過程當中 你表現得越悔恨...
The more penitent you show yourself through this whole process...
什么"過程"
The "process"?
這個"過程"的最終結果是什么
And what is this process to be?
那個先生的認罪書 已經開始在編寫中了
The confessions of the gentlemen are now being compiled.
你說什么
What?
你聽到他說的了
You heard him.
他們是不會袒護你的
They'll not lie for you.
那幾位先生將會被集體審訊
The gentlemen are to be tried together.
您和您的弟弟 身為貴族
You and your brother, being ennobled,
將由貴族們一起審判
are to be judged by your peers.
你沒有證人
You have no witnesses.
當您身處王后之位時 夫人
When you were at liberty, madam,
您的侍女們受你脅迫 被迫撒謊
your ladies were intimidated by you, forced to lie for you.
- 但現在她們無需再顧及... - 噢 我想也是
- Now, they are emboldened...- Oh, I'm sure they are.
就像西摩那樣
The way Seymour's emboldened.
替我轉告她 上帝能夠直視她的骯臟伎倆
Tell her from me, God sees her tricks.
等等
No!
告訴我...你不相信那些污蔑我的故事的 對嗎
Just tell me... You don't believe these stories against me, do you?
我知道你內心深處是不愿相信的
I know in your heart you don't.
對嗎 克倫威爾
Do you, Cremuel?
我的脖子很脆弱
I only have a little neck.
折斷它非常容易
So, it'll be the work of a moment.
你說過 一旦國王逝去
You said, when the King was dead,
你會從這些先生們中選一位當丈夫
you would choose one of these men to be your husband,
只是沒確定是哪位 你是否說過這樣的話
but you can't say which yet. Did you say that?
你必須大聲作出回答
You must answer a loud.
沒有
No.
說說你對我的指控
Read me your charges.
一條一條的說
Put them to me, one by one.
說出詳細的地點 約會內容
The places. The dates.
我會辯的你狼狽不堪
I'll confound you!
你是否聲明過 你永不會真心的愛國王
Did you not affirm that you could never love the King in your heart?
沒有
No.
你是否有在不同的時間 地點
Did you not, at various times and places, by kissing, touchings,
通過親吻 撫摸及身體接觸
and other infamous incitations,
勾引弗朗西斯·威斯頓 使其成為你的姘夫
induce Francis Weston to be your concubine?
沒有
No.
你是否有給國弗朗西斯·威斯頓大筆金錢作為禮物
Did you not make gifts of money to Francis Weston?
有
Yes.
肅靜
Silence!
這張紙上記載了 據說是王后對你說過的話
On this page are words the Queen is said to have spoken to you,
而你卻散播了這些話語
and which, in turn, you passed on.
不要念出聲來
Do not read them aloud.
就請告訴法庭 你是否記得這些話
Just tell the court, do you recognise them?
"國王無法與女人交媾
"The King cannot copulate with a woman.
他既沒技術 也沒精力"
He has neither skill, nor vigour."
這些話不是我說的...
I didn't say...
這不是我要說的話
These are not MY words.
不是我的原話
I don't own them!
可你剛剛已經說出口了
You do now.
經議會全員表決 現宣判被告
Having been found unanimously
有罪...
guilty...
再不安靜點就宰了你們
I'll do slaughter!
爾將被焚于倫敦塔內
Thou shalt be burned here, within the Tower.
或 將爾之顱砍去
Or else, to have thy head smitten off...
-...以顯國王之大度... - 這不公平
- ..as the King's pleasure... - That's not justice!
- 你們在說什么  - 怎么回事 怎么了?
- What are you talking about?  - What is it? What?
這些家伙說我的判決有誤
These fellows say I've done it wrong.
他們說我只能說"焚"這個字...
They say I have to say "burn" only...
這本就是國王的原話
The phrasing is the King's, and don't tell me
也別跟我說哪些能做 哪些不能 這可是我們第一次審判王后
what we can or can't do, we've never tried a queen before.
繼續把話說完 你們也坐下吧
Finish what you're saying. Sit down.
...將顱砍去
..head smitten off,
由此案 更可彰顯國王之大度
as the King's pleasure shall be further known of this matter...
她為什么一直盯著塔頂看
Why does she keep looking up at the tower?
因為她覺得一切仍有希望
Because she thinks there's still hope.
她沒辦法通過其他官員 告知我此事
So, she will not be able to tell me from the other officials.
她很快會解脫的
It will save her alarm.
善良的基督教徒們...
Good, Christian people...
..我是到此處來 是來受死的
..I am come hither to die.
因為根據法律判決 我被判了死刑
For according to the law, and by the law, I am judged to die -
我聽不清她的話
I can't hear her.
你認為她是在說臨終遺言嗎
You'd think she'd speak up for her last words.
我來此處 不為控訴任何人
I am come hither to accuse no man...
..也不為我是因何種控訴
..nor to speak any thing of that
如何判死刑 而辯解
whereof I am accused and condemned to die.
但我祈禱上帝來拯救國王...
But I pray God save the King...
..并愿他長壽 讓他的王位綿延萬世
..and send him long to reign over you.
因為從未有哪位王子 像他那般仁慈憐憫
For a gentler nor a more merciful prince was there never.
于我而言 他是從未有過的 正直紳士的 至高無上的君主
And, to me, was he ever a good, a gentle and a sovereign lord.
若后人想評論我的所作所為 我希望他們能公正評判
And if any person will meddle of my cause, I require them to judge best.
就這樣 我將告別這世界 告別你們
And thus I take my leave of the world and of you all,
我衷心希望你們能為我祈禱
and I heartily desire you all to pray for me.
主啊 請寬恕我的靈魂
Oh Lord, have mercy on my soul.
上帝 我把靈魂交付于你
To God, I commend my soul.
你會怎樣行刑
How will you do it?
讓她跪下
She kneels.
這樣就毫無阻礙了
There is no block.
基督 仁慈 耶穌 請收下我的靈魂...
Christ have mercy, Jesus receive my soul...
如果她不亂動的話 一下子就完事
If she is steady, it will be over in a moment.
一瞬間的事 她甚至都不會有一點痛感的
Between heartbeats. She knows nothing.
如果...她不亂動的話
IF...she is steady.
我可以確保 她不會亂動的
Well, I can answer for her.
把你的手臂放下來
Put your arm down.
持劍而來 奉命而歸
Apportez l'epee.
我們不想讓男人碰她的身體
We do not want men to handle her.
現在說這話 也太晚了哈 [暗指她亂交]
It's a little late for that!
對了
Right.
我要去告訴西摩家的人 一切都結束了
I'm off to tell the Seymours it's done.
彼以國士待我，我以國士待之，用過免費優質字幕服務，
而又有能力的人，有義務將這個免費服務做下去若有心加入我們
聯系 QQ群 428872140 更多影視請搜索并關注新浪微博  @大家字幕組
m -116 -16 l -102 -38 l -97 -38 l -109 -18 l -110 -19 l -110 -16 l -116 -16 m -96 -48 l -95 -41 l -100 -41 l -95 -48 m -85 -51 l -57 -51 l -57 -49 l -72 -49 l -72 -42 l -61 -42 l -61 -45 l -45 -45 l -43 -41 l -85 -41 l -85 -51 m -90 -30 l -99 -16 l -81 -16 l -90 -30 m -84 -38 l -60 -38 l -71 -34 l -71 -29 l -59 -34 l -56 -33 l -71 -26 l -71 -22 l -56 -28 l -56 -26 l -71 -20 l -71 -17 l -84 -38 m -50 -38 l -41 -38 l -39 -36 l -43 -36 l -45 -30 l -40 -16 l -47 -16 l -46 -18 l -46 -36 l -50 -38 m -36 -30 l -27 -16 l -31 -16 l -36 -30 m -56 -22 l -70 -16 l -61 -16 l -61 -18 l -56 -18 l -56 -22
六周的時間一晃而過  大家字幕組－英劇小部隊的第一部英劇正式完結了
這之中有心酸有快樂有苦悶有欣喜 但幸虧全組人都很有愛 都很努力
堅持做完了這部劇 感謝我們組的所有成員
組長靜宇  校對肉肉  時間軸特效Sandra
翻譯 Cindy  漢謨拉  小俊仔兒  叉叉  鑫鑫  抹茶蘇
翻譯  水水兒  筱欣  天然緋  熊叔  娃娃
壓制  大王  太陽雨  paradise 暴牙弟
請各位喜歡狼廳 喜歡英劇的童鞋們 繼續關注我們的新英劇喲
敬請關注我們的微博 @大家字幕組